mebelkart.com 2016-11-29

# Privacy Policy - MebelKart

This document is published in accordance with the provisions of Rule 4(1) of the Information Technology (Reasonable Security Practices and Procedures and Sensitive Personal Data or Information) Rules, 2011, which requires the publishing of a privacy policy for handling of or dealing in personal information including sensitive personal data or information. 

This Mebelkart Website (as defined below) is owned and operated by Getit Furniture Private Limited, a company incorporated under the provisions of the (Indian) Companies Act, 2013, having its registered office at 1205, 12th floor, New Delhi House, Barakhambha Road, New Delhi-110001 (hereinafter referred to as “Getit” “we” “us” or “our”). 

Any reference to “you” or “your” in this privacy policy (“ **Privacy Policy** ”), means you as a user of our website, [www.mebelkart.com](http://www.mebelkart.com/), or any other portal/subdomain as may be launched from time to time, including mobile and web applications and voice integration (“ **Mebelkart Website** ”) buying or selling the products and/or availing any of the services available on the Mebelkart Website (“ **User** ”). The afore-mentioned services of buying or selling the products and/or availing any of the services available on the Mebelkart Website, along with other services as may be included and modified from time to time, shall together be referred to as “ **Services** ”. 

As a User, your access to and use of the Mebelkart Website is governed by and conditional upon your acceptance of and continued compliance with this Privacy Policy at all times. By accessing, browsing, transacting and/or using the Mebelkart Website and/or availing any of the Services thereon, including but not limited to customer reviews, etc., you shall be subject to and you agree to be bound by this Privacy Policy and all rules, guidelines, policies, terms and conditions that are applicable to the Mebelkart Website for such transaction and/or Services being provided by Getit (“ **Policies** ”), as may be modified by Getit from time to time, which shall be deemed to be incorporated in this Privacy Policy by reference, unconditionally and at all times and further agree and confirm that you consent to providing Getit with your Personal Information (as defined below) for the purpose set out below and you understand that such collection, storage and handling is lawful, necessary and permissible under applicable laws. 

Each capitalized term not defined but used in this Privacy Policy shall have the same meaning as ascribed to such term in the Terms and Conditions (as defined below). 

**_Collection of Personal Information and other Information_** : 

Our Privacy Policy contains provisions regarding collection, storage and handling of personal and non-personal information that you share while availing the Services through the Mebelkart Website. These could include mandatory or voluntary disclosures that you make while and for using the Mebelkart Website. Personal Information is data that can be used to uniquely identify or contact a single person (“ **Personal Information** ”). Personal Information for the purposes of this Privacy Policy shall include, but not be limited to, your name, address, phone number, date of birth, gender, e-mail address, credit card / debit card / other payment instrument details, images, videos etc. provided by you whilst using the Mebelkart Website and/ or availing the Services or when you set up a free account with us. When you access, browse and/or use the Mebelkart Website, we collect and store your Personal Information, which is provided by you from time to time. Our primary goal in doing so is to provide you a safe, efficient, smooth and customized experience. This allows us to provide Services and features that most likely meet your needs and to customize the Mebelkart Website to make your experience safer and easier. More importantly, while doing so we collect Personal Information from you that we consider necessary for achieving this purpose. 

By accessing, browsing and continuing to use/browse the Mebelkart Website or by clicking on “Register” or “Submit” icons or other relevant icons/ buttons on the Mebelkart Website, you accept the terms of this Privacy Policy, and the fact that we store and process your Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

If you submit a comment or feedback on any business featured on the Mebelkart Website and/or any of the Services offered through the Mebelkart Website, we may (but are not obliged to) publish your comment online or offline to promote our business, products and Services. We will collect your name which will be displayed next to your comment, and e-mail address, which will not be published, but which we may use to contact you in relation to your comment. From time to time, we may ask you for your opinion on our Services. When we do surveys wherein we may use cookies or other on-device storage and may combine the information collected by those cookies or other on-device storage with your answers. We will make sure that the survey results do not identify you, or anyone else who fills in our surveys. 

In general, you can browse the Mebelkart Website without telling us who you are or revealing any Personal Information about yourself. Once you give us your Personal Information, you are not anonymous to us. Where possible, we indicate which fields are required and which fields are optional. You always have the option to not provide information by choosing not to use a particular Service or feature on the Mebelkart Website. We do not collect personally identifiable information (including Personal Information) about you, expect when you specifically provide such information on a voluntary basis. What we know about you we get mostly from you but we may also have to find out more about you from other sources in order to verify the information submitted by you, and to make sure that what we know about you is correct and complete. We may automatically track certain information about you based upon your behaviour on the Mebelkart Website. We use this information to do internal research on our Users' demographics, interests and behaviour to better understand, protect and serve our Users. This information is compiled and analysed on an aggregated basis. This information may include the URL that you just came from (whether this URL is on the Mebelkart Website or not), which URL you next go to (whether this URL is on the Mebelkart Website or not), your computer browser information, and your internet protocol address. This kind of verification is primarily done in order to address various security concerns, and to ensure that you comply with the provisions of applicable laws, and the terms and conditions available on the Mebelkart Website (“ **Terms and Conditions** ”) and other terms and conditions as may be prescribed by us from time to time. 

**_Use of Cookies_** : 

By using Mebelkart Website, our servers (hosted by a third party service provider) may collect information indirectly and automatically about your activities on the Mebelkart Website by way of data collection devices such as "cookies" and other such devices on certain pages of the Mebelkart Website to help analyse our web page flow, measure promotional effectiveness, and promote trust and safety, to compile anonymous, aggregated statistics that allow us to understand how Users use the Mebelkart Website and to help us improve the structure of the Mebelkart Website (we cannot identify you personally in this way). Further it allows us to understand who has seen which pages and advertisements on the Mebelkart Website, to determine how frequently particular such pages and advertisements are visited, to determine the most popular areas of the Mebelkart Website and generally in order to monitor usage of the Mebelkart Website. We may combine your visitor session information or other information collected through cookies and other technical methods with Personal Information in order to understand and improve your online experiences and to determine what category/nature of businesses and locations you prefer or are likely to be of interest to you. However, this information is not linked to your Personal Information and is maintained distinctly. A "cookie” is a small piece of information stored by a web server on a web browser on your hard drive so it can be later read back from that browser. Cookies are useful for enabling the browser to remember information specific to a given user and assist us in providing our Services. We place both permanent and temporary cookies in your computer's hard drive. The cookies do not contain any of your Personal Information. 

We offer certain features that are only available through the use of a "cookie". We also use cookies to allow you to enter your password less frequently during a session. Cookies can also help us provide information that is targeted to your interests. Most cookies are "session cookies," meaning that they are automatically deleted from your hard drive at the end of a session. You are always free to decline our cookies if your web browser permits by changing your web browser’s settings to accept or not to accept cookies, although in that case you may not be able to use certain features on the Mebelkart Website and you may be required to re-enter your password more frequently during a session. 

Getit could use log file including internet protocol addresses, browser type, internet service provider, referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyse trends, administer the Mebelkart Website, track user movement and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. These are not linked to your Personal Information. 

Additionally, you may encounter "cookies" or other similar devices on certain pages of the Mebelkart Website that are placed by third parties or by Linked Sites (as defined below). Getit may use third party service providers to serve advertisements on its behalf across the internet and sometimes on the Mebelkart Website. Such third party service providers may collect anonymous information about your visits to the Mebelkart Website. Personal Information is not linked to data collected from this source. We do not control these cookies placed by third parties/Linked Sites and once you have clicked on the advertisement and left the Mebelkart Website, our Privacy Policy no longer applies. Getit is not responsible for collection of cookies through Linked Sites, neither is it liable for misuse of the information you provide to Linked Sites. 

If you choose to buy any product/service through the Mebelkart Website, we collect information about your buying behaviour. 

If you transact with us, we collect some additional information, such as a billing address, a credit / debit card number and a credit / debit card expiration date and/ or other payment instrument details and tracking information from cheques or money orders. Kindly note that we do not store extremely sensitive information like your credit card information on our database. 

If you choose to post messages on our message boards, chat rooms or other message areas or leave feedback, we will collect that information you provide to us. We retain this information as necessary to resolve disputes, provide customer support and troubleshoot problems as permitted by law. 

If you send us personal correspondence, such as emails or letters, or if other users or third parties send us correspondence about your activities or postings on the Mebelkart Website, we may collect such information into a file specific to you. 

While you can browse some sections of our Mebelkart Website without being a registered member, certain activities (such as placing an order) do require registration. It is clarified that we store information only in the manner contained herein and in accordance with the provisions of applicable law. We do use your contact information provided at the time of registration to send you offers based on your previous orders and your interests. 

**_Use of Demographic / Profile Data / Your Information_** : 

Getit is sensitive towards your information including your Personal Information and non-personal information (email, business details, demographic location and address, age, name, phone number etc.,) provided at the time of registering with Getit or otherwise while availing the Services on the Mebelkart Website. We use information about you to help us provide you with a more personalized Service, which is tailored to suit your needs. 

The information is readily available on the Mebelkart Website and only viewable by you by logging on to the Mebelkart Website. You, at all times have the option not to provide any Personal Information or other information about you without agreeing to register with Getit and otherwise withdraw your consent by communicating the same to us in the manner specified in the Terms and Conditions and the Policies. Upon withdrawal Getit will have no obligations towards you nor will it be liable for the Services and products provided till the time you had consented to retain the information with Getit. Please note that if you “do not agree” to, or “opt out” from, providing Personal Information or other information requested by us, you may not be able to access certain areas of the Mebelkart Website and/or avail certain Services. However, it may be noted that Getit reserves the right to send Service related and your specific and preferred transaction related communication without offering you the facility to opt-out. You can update your Account Details (as defined below), Personal Information and other information at any time. At your request, Getit can also cancel your registration and remove/block your Personal Information from its database/Mebelkart Website. However, this information may remain in our archive even after deletion or termination of your account as required by law and the handling of the same is in accordance with the provisions of the applicable law and as intimated by the government agency from time to time. 

**_We use Personal Information to: n_** : 

(i) assist in and provide the Services you request; 

(ii) monitor, develop and improve the Mebelkart Website, Services and your experience; 

(iii) process and deal with any complaints or enquiries made by or about you; and 

(iv) investigate any suspected breach of the [Terms and Conditions ](http://www.mebelkart.com/content/3-terms-and-conditions-of-use)or the breach of other terms and conditions otherwise relating to you and to monitor compliance including by way of checking postings or submissions to the Mebelkart Website; 

(v) resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, and help promote a safe Service; 

(vi) collect money; 

(vii) measure consumer interest in the Services offered by Getit and the products/services listed on the Mebelkart Website; 

(vii) detect and protect us against error, fraud and other criminal activity; 

(viii) enforce our Terms and Conditions; and 

(ix) as otherwise described to you at the time of collection. 

**_Where and only where requested/agreed by you, we will:_**

(i) send you and keep you updated with information by email, telephone (including SMS) or mail about existing and new Services and special offers from us; 

(ii) send you information by email, telephone or mail about related products or services of selected third parties that may be of interest to you. 

To the extent we use your Personal Information to market to you and inform you about online and offline offers, products, Services, and updates, we will provide you the ability to opt-out of such uses. 

In our efforts to continually improve our product and Service offerings, we collect and analyse demographic and profile data about our Users' activity on the Mebelkart Website. We identify and use your internet protocol address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer the Mebelkart Website. Your internet protocol address is also used to help identify you and to gather broad demographic information. 

We will occasionally ask you to complete optional online surveys. These surveys may ask you for contact information and demographic information (like zip code, age, or income level). We use this data to tailor your experience at the Mebelkart Website, providing you with content that we think you might be interested in and to display content according to your preferences. 

**_Sharing of Personal Information:_**

For any payments on the Mebelkart Website, Getit uses online payment gateway operated by third parties and the information that you provide at the time of making a purchase on the Mebelkart Website is held and stored with third party payment gateway operators authorised at multiple points. The payment gateway operator may also have access to your online purchase history/details that you make from the Mebelkart Website. These payment gateways are digitally encrypted, thereby providing the highest possible degree of privacy and care available, currently. Whilst we are unable to guarantee 100% (one hundred percent) security, this makes it hard for a hacker to decrypt your details. You are strongly recommended not to send full credit or debit card details in unencrypted electronic communications with us. Also, you are responsible for protecting against unauthorised access to your password and to your computer. We will not be liable for the disclosure and dissemination of Personal Information to third parties which you as prudent Users put up on the Mebelkart Website, and available to the other Users of the Mebelkart Website. 

Kindly note that we do not store extremely sensitive information like your credit card information on our database. 

Getit, handles all information in accordance with the provisions of the applicable law as made applicable from time to time and only for the duration lawfully required, thereunder. Getit may disclose aggregated information, including to aggregators, about the use of the Mebelkart Website without Personal Information. Getit implements standard measures to protect against unauthorized access to and unlawful interception of Personal Information. However, Getit feels prudent to inform you that no website can fully eliminate security risks and enforcement of privacy laws are at a developing stage in some parts of the world. 

**_Storage of Information:_**

Getit does not rent, sell or share your personal or sensitive information and does not disclose any of your Personal Information to third parties unless you have granted Getit the permission to do so. However, we may pass your Personal Information to other third parties in the following scenarios: 

(i) To help us process questions you may have about Services, registration or other inquiry you may have; 

(ii) To confirm or correct what we know about you; 

(iii) We may pass your Personal Information to our employees, contractors, suppliers and/or agents to administer the Services provided to you by us now or in the future; 

(iv) If you call our customer care call centre, we may pass your Personal Information to our call centre to allow them to deal with your call more efficiently; 

(v) Assisting any government agency or regulatory authority in undertaking information for us; 

(vi) If another organization is engaged by us to perform tasks on our behalf; 

(vii) Compliance with an audit on our business; 

(viii) If we use third party processors to administer and process your Personal Information for the purposes notified in the Privacy Policy, e.g. for hosting activities related to the use of the Mebelkart Website or Services; 

(ix) To obtain advice from third parties such as auditors or legal advisors; 

(x) We may share Personal Information with our other corporate entities and affiliates to help detect and prevent identity theft, fraud and other potentially illegal acts, correlate related or multiple accounts to prevent abuse of our Services, and to facilitate joint or co-branded Services that you request where such Services are provided by more than one corporate entity. Those entities and affiliates may not market to you as a result of such sharing unless you explicitly opt-in.We may also disclose Personal Information if required to do so by law, for legal proceedings or in the good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process or any applicable law, regulation, government, regulatory or other authority, agency or officer requires it or to protect the safety or security of users of the Mebelkart Website. We may disclose Personal Information to law enforcement offices, third party rights owners, or others in the good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to enforce our Terms and Conditions, Policies or this Privacy Policy, respond to claims that an advertisement, posting or other content violates the rights of a third party, or protect the rights, property or personal safety of our Users or the general public or prevent fraud, money laundering, terrorism and other crimes. 

We and our affiliates will share some or all of your Personal Information with another business entity should we (or our assets) plan to merge with, or be acquired by that business entity, or re­organization, amalgamation, restructuring of business or if we intend to sell all or any part of our assets, undertakings or business to such other business entity. Should such a transaction occur then that other business entity (or the new combined entity) will be required to follow this Privacy Policy with respect to your Personal Information; 

These entities and affiliates for the purposes of this Privacy Policy shall mean a company in which Getit directly or indirectly, owns or controls, or is owned or controlled by, or is under common ownership or control with Getit, wherein ‘own’ means the beneficial ownership of or the ability to direct the voting of more than 20% (twenty percent) of the total share capital or rights to distributions on account of equity of Getit and ‘control’ shall include the right to appoint majority of the directors or to control the management or policy decisions exercisable by a person or persons acting individually or in concert, directly or indirectly, including by virtue of their shareholding or management rights or shareholders agreements or voting agreements or in any other manner. 

In addition to the above, disclosures may also be made if it was clearly stated at the time of registration and, where required, if you have given permission for such disclosures. 

Generally, we will disclose only the information we consider reasonably necessary to disclose. Also, some general statistical information about the Mebelkart Website user base, traffic volumes and related matters may be passed on to reputable third parties but these details will not include your Personal Information. 

**_Links to Other Sites:_**

Please note that this Privacy Policy does not cover any third-party websites and/or applications to which we provide links in the Mebelkart Website, nor does it cover advertisers. They may have their own privacy policies and/or terms and conditions of use. We use third-party advertisers to serve advertisements when you visit the Mebelkart Website. These third party agencies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to the Mebelkart Website and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods, products and services of interest to you. The Mebelkart Website provides links to other third-party websites that may collect Personal Information about you (hereinafter third-party websites/applications/advertisers are collectively referred to as “ **Linked Site** ”). 

We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these Linked Sites and no Personal Information is provided to these Linked Sites by us. Getit clarifies that the Linked Sites are operated by third parties and are not under control of or affiliation or association of Getit unless specifically expressed by Getit. Getit is not responsible for any form of transmission, material received from any Linked Site. We are not liable and do not represent anything regarding the privacy practices and policies adopted by the Linked Sites and their owners/operators. Also, we are not in a position to control or guarantee the accuracy, integrity or quality of the information, data, text, software, music, sound, photographs, graphics, videos, messages or other relevant materials available on the Linked Sites. 

Providing the Linked Sites on Getit do not imply or convey any endorsement by Getit in any manner or of the contents of the Linked Site. You are aware that the information you provide on the Linked Sites shall be governed by policies of the Linked Sites, which you view. Getit does not have power or authority to prevent misuse of your information through the Linked Sites. 

Linked Sites may use technology to send the advertisements on the Mebelkart Website directly to your browser because of which the Linked Sites automatically receive your internet protocol address. They may use cookies, java script, web beacons and other technologies to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and to personalize advertising content. Getit has no access or control over cookies or other features of the Linked Sites and these are not governed by this Privacy Policy. 

**_Security Precautions:_**

We strive to ensure the security, integrity protection and privacy of your Personal Information against unauthorized access, unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction. The Mebelkart Website has stringent security measures, techniques and requirements in place for handling sensitive and Personal Information and to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the Personal Information under our control. These measures, techniques and requirements are fully compliant with the guidelines set forth under applicable law. Whenever you change or access your Account Details, we offer the use of a secure server. Our servers are accessible only to authorized personnel. Your information logged under this Privacy Policy is shared with respective personnel only on need to know basis and/ or to provide the Services you have requested. All representatives handling information under these provisions are under contractual confidentiality obligation with Getit. Once your information is in our possession we adhere to strict security guidelines, protecting it against unauthorized access. While, we take every step to safeguard the confidentiality of your Personal Information, by using this Mebelkart Website, you agree and confirm that Getit is not liable for any disclosure due to errors in transmission or unauthorized acts of third parties or Linked Sites. 

Notwithstanding the foregoing, you must keep account details, including your username and password (“ **Account Details** ”) confidential at all times, and should not reveal the same to any third parties. You must take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized disclosure of your Account Details (including logging out from your account at the end of each session), and you must notify us immediately if your Account Details becomes known to any unauthorized user. You are solely responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your Account Details, and all activities that occur under your account(s). Any breach of this Privacy Policy by anyone to whom you disclose your account details, including your username and password will be treated as if the breach had been committed by you, and will not relieve you of your obligations under the Terms and Conditions. 

Notwithstanding anything contained herein, Getit shall not be liable for any loss, damage or misuse of your Personal Information due to a force majeure event. A force majeure event for the purposes of this Privacy Policy shall mean any event that is beyond reasonable control of Getit and shall include, without limitation, sabotage, fire, flood, explosion, acts of God, civil commotion, strikes or industrial action of any kind, riots, insurrection, war, acts of government, computer hacking, unauthorised access to computer data and storage device, computer viruses breach of security and encryption or any other cause beyond the control of Getit. 

**_Use of information for marketing & Choice/Opt-Out: _**

In line with any permission given by you to us, we may send you direct marketing communications about our own, or our partners’/selected third parties’ services and disclose your information to other organizations who may send direct marketing communications to you. You can change your marketing preferences if you are registered with us. In addition, we provide all Users with the opportunity to opt-out of receiving non-essential (promotional, marketing-related) communications from us on behalf of our partners/third party service providers, and from us in general, after setting up an account by unsubscribing from email communications via unsubscribe links provided in communications sent to you. 

If you want to remove your contact information from all mebelkart.com lists and newsletters, please visit [ http://www.mebelkart.com (http://www.mebelkart.com/)](http://www.mebelkart.com/)

**_Your Consent:_**

By using the Mebelkart Website, using the Services and/ or by providing your information/registering with Mebelkart Website, you are deemed to have agreed to the terms of this Privacy Policy and you consent to the collection and use of the information you disclose on the Mebelkart Website in accordance with this Privacy Policy, including but not limited to your consent for sharing your information as per this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy should be at all times read along with the Terms and Conditions and the Policies. The Privacy Policy applies to all information, including Personal Information and Account Details. 

By using the Services, you agree and acknowledge that your Personal Information may be transferred across national boundaries and stored and processed in any country around the world. You acknowledge that in the process of providing the Services under the Mebelkart Website, some activities relating to handling of information collected under the Privacy Policy may be done by Getit’s trusted third party vendors or agents, web hosting providers, communication services, and web analytic providers. 

**Changes _to this Privacy Policy:_**

We reserve the right, in our sole discretion, to change, modify, add or remove any portions of or whole of this Privacy Policy at any time without any prior written notice or intimation. If we decide to change this Privacy Policy, we will post those changes as contained in the latest version of the same on the Mebelkart Website so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it. 

It is hereby clarified that it is your responsibility to check and review this Privacy Policy from time to time, in order to keep yourself updated of the same. Your continued use of the Mebelkart Website following any amendment of this Privacy Policy and posting of the changes to it, will signify and constitute your consent to and acceptance of the revised Privacy Policy and the changes therein. We will not file or store a copy of these terms for each interaction on transaction by you via the Mebelkart Website. We therefore recommend that you save a copy of this Privacy Policy for future reference, and ensure that such copies can be reliably verified as being effective (i.e. published on the Mebelkart Website) on a particular date. 

**_Grievance Officer:_**

Thank you for reading our Privacy Policy and thank you for choosing our Mebelkart Website. In accordance with Information Technology Act, 2000 and rules made thereunder, the name and contact details of the Grievance Officer are provided below: 

**Getit Furniture Private Limited,**

1205, 12th floor, New Delhi House, Barakhambha Road, New Delhi-110001 

If you have any questions about anything contained in the Privacy Policy, you can email us with any questions, queries or complaints by contacting our customer care service at: [legal@mebelkart.com](mailto:legal@mebelkart.com) or contact: +918067978888 (10:30 a.m. - 8 p.m.) ****

**_Disputes:_**

Any disputes over inter alia collection, storage and handling of Personal Information will be governed by this Privacy Policy, Terms and Conditions and by the laws of India and courts of New Delhi shall have exclusive jurisdiction. 

**_Questions:_**

Any questions or communication regarding this Privacy Policy should be directed to the following address: [legal@mebelkart.com](mailto:legal@mebelkart.com)

Our privacy policy is subject to change at any time without notice. To make sure you are aware of any changes, please review this policy periodically. 

By visiting this Mebelkart Website you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree please do not use or access our Website. 

By mere use of the Mebelkart Website, you expressly consent to our use and disclosure of your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and subject to the Terms of Use.
